Matthew Richardson

ECOLOGIST - GIS TECHNICIAN

EDUCATION

2014 - 2018

 ${\bf BS} \; {\bf ENVIRONMENTAL} \; {\bf BIOLOGY}$

Fort Lewis College - Durango, CO

2014 - 2018

GEOGRAPHIC INFORMATION SYSTEMS CERT.

Fort Lewis College - Durango, CO

2010 - 2014

High School

Vandegrift High School - Austin, TX

STATEMENT

An experienced ecologist with an expertise in warm-dry mixed conifer forests. Using geospatial data I have expanded knowledge on the current extent of ecological issues and predicted their future impacts. By combining ecological data with GIS technology, developments can be more sustainable and cause less environmental impact while withstanding future disturbances.

SKILLS

Surveying / GPS

Adobe Creative Suite

Digital/Film Photography

Woodworking

HTML, CSS, PYTHON, GIT

EXPERIENCE

May 2018 - September 2018 FORESTY TECHNICIAN/BOTANIST

Fort Lewis College - Northern Arizona U.

Performed data collection on forestry and botany attributes in a 800-acre wilderness research area. Identification of taxon using a dichotomous key within modified whittaker plots. Standard ecological tools used for forestry metrics. Required excellent physical condition.

January 2018 - May 2018 RESEARCH ASSISTANT

Dr. Julie Korb, Fort Lewis College

In collaboration with the San Juan Forest Service and Fort Lewis College, I helped develop a mapping site for the public domain regarding the Missionary Fire. Goal: to provide mapping of data and comparison photos. Created using Google Maps, Mapbox and ArcMap. Link.

Spring 2016 - Fall 2018 SUDDEN ASPEN DECLINE RESEARCH Biology Department at Fort Lewis College

Predicting future changes in extent of Aspen range using GIS spatial analysis. Extent analyzed using collected pathogen data and forestry metrics. Data collection method was designed using Gaia GPS for a more efficient collection process.

Fall 2016 - Spring 2018 GIS / ECOLOGY TEACHER ASSISTANT Fort Lewis College

Providing Fort Lewis College GIS and ecology students with assistance of class and lab work. Additional study hours were held providing in depth course discussion of topics, systems and tools.

CONTACT

782 Florida Rd, Durango, Colorado, 81301

T: 512-968-1421

E: matthewdrichardson08@gmail.com www.mdrichardson.com

SOCIAL MEDIA

- Instagram
- Twitter
- <u>LinkedIN</u>
- Strava

INTERESTS

- Mountain Running
- · Backcountry Skiing
- · Film Photography
- Music

REFERENCES

Dr. Julie Korb

Biology Department at Fort Lewis College T: 970 382 6905 E: korb_j@fortlewis.edu

Dr. Cynthia Dott

Biology Department at Fort Lewis College T: 970 247 7322 E: dott_c@fortlewis.edu

Scott White

Gelogy Department at Fort Lewis College **T**: 970 247 7475 **E**: white_s@fortlewis.edu